Steel Magnolias is a romance, drama, tv movie film directed by Kenny Leon.
In an updated contemporary version of the beloved stage play and 1989 film, "Steel
Magnolias" chronicles the lives and friendship of six women in Louisiana.
Supporting each other through their triumphs and tragedies, they congregate at Truvy’s beauty shop to ponder the mysteries of life
and death, husbands and children - and hair and nails - all the important topics that truly unite and celebrate women.
M'Lynn, played by Queen Latifah.
Ouiser, played by Alfre Woodard.
Clairee, played by Phylicia Rashād.
Truvy, played by Jill Scott.
Annelle, played by Adepero Oduye.
Shelby, played by Dola Rashad.
Steel Magnolias is an American comedy-drama television film directed by Kenny
Leon that premiered at Lifetime Network on October 7, 2012.
It is a contemporary retelling of the play Steel
Magnolias and its 1989 film adaptation.
The new film stars an all-black American cast, including Queen Latifah as M'Lynn, Jill Scott as Truvy, Condola
Rashad as Shelby, Adepero Oduye as Annelle, with Phylicia Rashad as Clairee and Alfre Woodard as Ouiser.
The film marks the first collaboration between Latifah and
Scott (the second being Flint in 2017).
The tone is emotional.